I would be remiss on this special
occasion if I did not say thank you for
using your t-shirt wardrobe to
demonstrate to the world that male
sartorial elegance doesn't always
present itself in a suit tie and
cufflinks most importantly thank you for
being with us today on our special day
ladies and gentlemen it is my high honor
to introduce dr. Mark Zuckerberg
I love this place thank you all for
coming out in the rain the pouring rain
we're gonna make this worth it for you
president Faust Board of Overseers
faculty friends alumni proud parents
members of the ad board and graduates of
the greatest university in the world
I am honored to be here with you today
because let's face it you accomplished
something I never could if I get through
this speech today it'll be the first
time I actually finished something here
at Harvard class of 2017 congratulations
now I'm an unlikely speaker today not
just because I dropped out but because
we're technically in the same generation
we walk this yard less than a decade
apart we studied the same ideas and
slept through the same act 10 lectures
we may have taken different roads to get
here especially if you came all the way
from the quad but today I want to share
what I've learned about our generation
and the world we're all building
together but first these the last couple
of days have brought back a lot of good
memories how many of you remember
exactly where you were and what you were
doing when you got that email telling
you you got into Harvard
I was playing I was playing the video
game civilization and I ran downstairs
and got my dad and for some reason his
first reaction was to video me opening
the email that could have been a really
really sad video but I swear getting
into Harvard is the thing my parents are
most proud of me for my mom is nodding
you all know what I'm talking about look
guys it's tough to beat this you'll see
when you get out there how many of you
remember your first lecture here at
Harvard mine was computer science 121
with the incredible Harry Lewis Harry I
was running late for class so I throw on
a t-shirt and I didn't realize until
afterwards as I put it on inside out and
backwards my tag was sticking out the
front I couldn't figure out why no one
in class would talk to me except for
this one guy K X Gen he just went with
it we started doing our problem sets
together and now he runs a big part of
Facebook and that class of 2017 is why
you should be nice to people but my best
memory from Harvard is meeting Priscilla
I had just launched this prank website
Facemash and the ad board wanted to see
me everyone thought I was going to get
kicked out my parents drove up here to
help me pack my stuff my friends threw
me a going-away party who does that as
luck would have it Priscilla was at that
party with her friends and we met in
line for the bathroom in the pfoho bell
tower and then what must be one of the
all-time most romantic lines I turned
her and said I'm getting kicked out in
three days so we need to go on to date
quickly actually any of you graduating
today can use that line I'm getting
kicked out today we need to go on a date
fast I didn't end up getting kicked out
I did that to myself Priscilla and I
started dating and you know that movie
made it seem like Facemash was so
important to starting Facebook it wasn't
but without Facemash I never would have
met Priscilla and Priscilla is the most
important person in my life so you could
still say it was the most important
thing I built in my time here
we have all started lifelong friendships
here and some of us even families that's
why I'm so grateful to this place thanks
Harvard today I want to talk about
purpose but I'm not here to give you the
standard commencement about finding your
purpose
we're Millennials we try to do that
instinctively instead I'm here to tell
you that finding your purpose isn't
enough the challenge for our generation
is to create a world where everyone has
a sense of purpose one of my favorite
stories is when JFK went to go visit the
NASA Space Center and he saw a janitor
holding a broom and he asked him what he
was doing and the janitor replied mr.
president I'm helping put a man on the
moon purpose is that feeling that you
are a part of something bigger than
yourself that you are needed and that
you have something better ahead to work
for purpose is what creates true
happiness and you are graduating at a
time when this is especially important
when our parents graduated that sense of
purpose reliably came from your job your
church your community but today
technology and automation are
eliminating many jobs membership in a
lot of communities has been declining
and a lot of people are feeling
disconnected and depressed and are
trying to fill a void in their lives as
I've traveled around I've sat with
children and juvenile detention and
opioid addicts so you've told me that
maybe their lives would have turned out
differently if they just had something
to do and after school program or
somewhere to go I've met factory workers
who know their old jobs aren't coming
back and we're just trying to find their
path ahead for our society to keep
moving forward we have a generational
challenge to not only create new job
but create a renewed sense of purpose I
remember that night I launched Facebook
from that little dorm in Kirkland house
I went to Noakes with my friend kayaks
and I remember telling him clearly that
I was excited to help connect the
Harvard community but one day someone
would connect the whole world the thing
is it never even occurred to me that
that someone might be us we were just
college kids we don't know anything
about that there are all these great big
technology companies with all these
resources and I just assumed one of them
would do it but this idea was so clear
to us that all people want to connect so
we just kept working on it day after day
after day and I know that a lot of you
are going to have your own stories just
like this a change in the world that
seems so clear that you are sure someone
else is going to do it but they're not
you will but it's not enough to have
that purpose yourself you also have to
create a sense of purpose for others and
I found that out the hard way you see my
hope was never to build a company I
wanted to have an impact and as all
these people started joining us I just
assumed that that's what they wanted to
do too so I never took the time to
explain what it was that I hoped we'd
build a couple years in some big
companies wanted to buy us I didn't want
to sell I wanted to see if we could
connect more people and we were building
the first version of newsfeed at the
time and I thought if we could just
launch this it could change how we all
learn about the world nearly everyone
else wanted to sell without a sense of
higher purpose
this was their startup dream come true
and it tore our company apart after one
particularly tense argument one of my
closest advisors told me if I didn't
agree to sell the company right now I
would regret that decision for the rest
of my life relationships were so afraid
that within a year or so every single
person on our management team was gone
that was my hardest time meeting
Facebook I believed in what we were
doing but I felt alone and worse it was
my fault I wondered if I was just wrong
an imposter a 22 year old kid who had no
idea how things actually worked now
years later I understand it that is how
things work when there's no sense of
higher purpose so it's up to all of us
to create it so we can all keep moving
forward together and today I want to
talk about three ways that we can create
a world where everyone has a sense of
purpose by taking on big meaningful
projects together by redefining equality
so everyone has the freedom to pursue
their purpose and by building community
all across the world so first let's take
on big meaningful projects our
generation is going to have to deal with
tens of millions of jobs replaced by
automation like self-driving cars and
trucks but we have the potential to do
so much more than that every generation
has its defining works more than three
hundred thousand people work to put that
man on the moon including that janitor
millions of volunteers immunize children
around the world against polio and
millions of more people built the Hoover
Dam and other great projects and now
it's our generations turn to do great
things now I know maybe you're thinking
I don't know how to build a dam I don't
know how to get a million people
involved in anything well let me tell
you a secret
no one does when they begin ideas don't
come out fully formed they only become
clear as you work on them you just have
to get started if I had to know
everything about connecting people
before I got started I never would have
built Facebook movies and pop culture
just get this all wrong
the idea of a single Eureka moment is a
dangerous lie it makes us feel
inadequate because we feel like we
haven't had ours yet and it prevents
people with seeds of good ideas from
ever getting started in the first place
oh and you know what else movies get
wrong about innovation no one writes
math formulas on glass okay all right
that's not a thing okay it's really good
to be idealistic
but be prepared to be misunderstood
anyone working on a big vision is going
to get called crazy even if you end up
right anyone taking on a complex problem
is going to get blamed for not fully
understanding it even though it's
impossible to know everything up front
anyone taking initiative will always get
criticized for moving too fast because
there's always someone who wants to slow
you down in our society we often don't
take on big things because we're so
afraid of making mistakes that we ignore
all the things wrong today if we do
nothing the reality is anything we do
today is going to have some issues in
the future but that can't stop us from
getting started so what are we waiting
for
it is time for our generation defining
great works how about stopping climate
change before we destroy the planet and
getting millions of people involved
manufacturing and installing solar
panels how about curing all diseases and
getting people involved by asking
volunteers to share their health data
track their health data and share their
genomes you know today our society
spends more than 50 times as much
treating people who are sick as we
invest in finding cures so people get
sick in the first place
it makes no sense we can fix this how
about modernizing democracy so everyone
can vote online
and how about personalizing education so
everyone can learn these achievements
are all within our reach let's do them
all in a way that gives everyone in our
society a role
let's do big things not just to create
progress but to create purpose so taking
on big meaningful projects together is
the first thing we can do to create a
world where everyone has a sense of
purpose
the second is redefining our idea of
equality so everyone has the freedom to
pursue their purpose now many of our
parents had stable jobs throughout their
careers but in our generation we're all
a little entrepreneurial whether we're
starting our own projects or finding our
role in another one and you know that's
great because our culture of
entrepreneurship is how we create so
much progress an entrepreneurial culture
thrives when it is easy to try lots of
new ideas Facebook wasn't the first
thing I built I also built chat systems
and games study tools and music players
and I'm not alone JK Rowling got
rejected 12 times before she finally
wrote and published Harry Potter even
Beyonce
had to make hundreds of songs to get
halo the greatest successes come from
having the freedom to fail now today we
have a level of wealth and equality that
hurts everyone when you can't when you
don't have the freedom to take your idea
and turn it into a historic enterprise
we all lose and right now today our
society is way over indexed on rewarding
people when they're successful and we
don't do nearly enough to make sure that
everyone can take lots of different
shots
let's face it there is something wrong
with our system when I can leave here
and make billions of dollars in ten
years while millions of students can't
even afford to pay off their loans let
alone start a business look I know a lot
of entrepreneurs and I don't know a
single person who gave up on starting a
business because they were worried they
might not make enough money but I know
too many people who haven't had the
chance to pursue their dreams because
they didn't have a cushion to fall back
on if they failed we all know you don't
get successful just by having a good
idea or working hard you get successful
by being lucky - if I had to support my
family growing up instead of having the
time to learn how to code if I didn't
know that I was going to be fine if
Facebook didn't work out then I wouldn't
be standing up here today and if we were
honest we all know how much luck we've
had to get to this point in our lives
every generation expands its definition
of equality previous generations fought
for the vote and civil rights they had
the New Deal and Great Society and now
it's time for our generation to define a
new social contract
we should have a society that measures
progress not just by economic metrics
like GDP but by how many of us have a
role we find meaningful we should
explore ideas like universal basic
income to make sure that everyone has a
cushion to try new ideas we're all going
to change jobs and roles many times so
we need affordable childcare to get to
work and healthcare that's not tied to
just one employer and we're all going to
make mistakes so we need a society
that's less focused on locking us up and
stigmatizing us when we do and as our
technology keeps on evolving we need a
society that is more focused on
providing continuous education through
our lives and yes giving everyone the
freedom to pursue purpose isn't going to
be free people like me should pay for it
and a lot of you are going to do really
well and you should too
that is why Priscilla and I started the
Chan Zuckerberg initiative and committed
our wealth to promoting equal
opportunity these are the values of our
whole generation it was never a question
of if we were going to do this the only
question was when Millennials are
already one of the most charitable
generations in history in just one year
more than three and four u.s.
Millennials donated to charity and more
than seven and ten raise money for
another one but it's not just about
giving money you can also give time and
I promise you if you just take an hour
to a week that's all it takes to give
someone a hand and help them reach their
potential now maybe you're thinking
that's a lot of time I'm not sure if I
have that much time I used to think that
you know when Priscilla graduated from
Harvard she became a teacher and before
she'd do education work with me she told
me that I needed to get my own
experience teaching a class at first I
complained you know I'm kind of busy
running this company but she insisted so
I taught an after-school program at the
local Boys and Girls Club on
entrepreneurship I taught those kids
lessons on product development and
marketing and they taught me what it was
like growing up feeling targeted for
your race and what it's like having a
family member in prison
I shared stories of my time in school
and they shared their hope that one day
they would get to go to college - for
five years I've had dinner with those
students every month one of them even
through Priscilla and me our first baby
shower and next year they're going to
college
every one of them first generation and
their families we can all make time to
give someone a hand let's give everyone
the freedom to pursue purpose not just
because it's the right thing to do but
because when more people can turn their
dreams into something great we are all
better for it
[Applause]
purpose doesn't only come from work
the third way we can create a sense of
purpose for everyone
is by building community and in our
generation when we say purpose for
everyone we mean everyone in the world
now quick show of hands how many of you
here are from another country I now keep
your hands up how many of you are
friends with one of these folks now
we're talking
see we have we have grown up connected
in a recent survey of Millennials around
the world asking what most defines our
identity the most popular answer wasn't
nationality ethnicity or religion
it was citizen of the world that's a big
deal every generation expands the circle
of people we consider one of us and in
our generation that now includes the
whole world we understand that the great
arc of human history bends towards
people coming together in ever greater
numbers from tribes to cities to nations
to achieve things that we could not on
our own we get that our greatest
opportunities are now global we can be
the generation that ends poverty that
ends disease and we get that our
greatest challenges need global
responses to no country can fight
climate change alone or prevent
pandemics progress now requires coming
together not just as cities or nation
but also as a global community but we
live in an unstable time there are
people left behind by globalization
across the whole world and it's tough to
care about people in other places well
we don't first feel good about our lives
here at home there's pressure to turn
inwards this is the struggle of our time
the forces of freedom openness and
global community against the forces of
authoritarianism isolationism and
nationalism forces for the flow of
knowledge trade and immigration against
those who would slow them down this is
not a battle of Nations it is a battle
of ideas there are people in every
country for more global connection and
there are good people against it and
this isn't going to be decided the UN
either it's going to happen at the local
level when enough of us feel a sense of
purpose and stability and our own lives
that we can start to open up and care
about everyone else too and the best way
to do that is to start building local
communities right now
we all get a lot of meaning from our
communities who hears from Elliot house
how about Lowell I know you guys found
community because you literally live
right on top of each other and Mather
I'll just leave that there whether our
communities are houses or sports teams
churches or acapella groups they give us
that sense that we were a part of
something bigger that we are not alone
they give us the strength to expand our
horizons and that's why it's so striking
that over the past few decades
membership in all kinds of communities
has declined by as much as one quarter
that's a lot of people who now need to
find a sense of purpose somewhere else
but I know that we can rebuild these
communities and start new ones because
many of you already are I met Agnes
ps-agui who's graduating today Agnes
where are you
agnus spent her childhood navigating
conflict zones with human trafficking in
Uganda and now she's trained thousands
of law enforcement officials to keep
communities safe
I'm at Kayla Oakley and Neha Jain
graduating today to stand up guys
Kayla Nia started a non-profit that
connects people suffering from chronic
illnesses with people in their
communities who are willing to help out
and I met David Rosner he was graduating
from the Kennedy School today David
stand up David is a former city
councilor who fought to make Mexico City
the first Latin American city to pass
marriage equality even before San
Francisco and this is my story too
a student in a dorm connecting one
community at a time and keeping at it
until one day we can connect the whole
world change starts local even Global
Change starts small with people like us
in our generation the struggle of
whether we connect more whether we
achieve our greatest opportunities comes
down to this your ability to build
communities and create a world where
every single person has a sense of
purpose
class of 2017 you are graduating into a
world that needs purpose and it's up to
you to create it now maybe you're asking
yourself can I really do this well
remember when I told you about that
class I taught at the Boys & Girls Club
one day after class I was talking to my
students about going to college and one
of my top students raised his hand and
said that he wasn't sure he could go to
college because he's undocumented he
wasn't sure if they'd take him
last year I took him out to breakfast
for his birthday and I wanted to get him
a gift so I asked him what he wanted and
he just started talking about struggles
that he saw other students in his class
facing and finally said you know I'd
really just like a book on social
justice I was blown away here is a young
guy who has every reason to be cynical
he wasn't sure if the country he calls
home the only one he's known was going
to deny him his dream of going to
college but he wasn't feeling sorry for
himself he wasn't even thinking of
himself he has a greater sense of
purpose and he's going to bring people
along with him it says something about
our situation today that I can't even
say his name because I don't want to put
him at risk but if a high school senior
who doesn't know what the future holds
for him can do his part to move the
world forward then we owe it to the
world to do our part to
so before you walk out those gates one
last time and as we sit here in front of
Memorial Church I'm reminded of a prayer
Misha Barak that I say whenever I face a
big challenge that I sing to my daughter
thinking of her future when I tuck her
in at night and it goes may the source
of strength whose blessed the ones
before us help us find the courage to
make our lives a blessing I hope you
find the courage to make your life a
blessing congratulations class of 2017
good luck out there
[Applause]